

Evgenii Kotelnikov, Ph.D.

Date of birth: 15 February 1990

Current location: Gothenburg, Sweden (open to relocation)

I am a software developer and a computer scientist dedicated to building complex reliable software.

My academic background is in formal methods, static analysis and functional programming.

Over the last 15 years I worked as a software developer within Cloud, Web, Telecom and Automotive.

I worked with many tech stacks over the years, and my preferred ones are C, Python, Scala and HaskelI.

Work experience

in My LinkedIn profile

Zenseact AB

February 2021 to now 🛗

Software developer

Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Zenseact develops an autonomous driving platform for Volvo Cars. Develop safety critical software components of self-driving cars in C, C++ and Ada.

- Scout for requirements, breakdown, refine and formalize. • Integrate the SPARK verification toolchain into the company's codebase.
- Formally verify safety requirements of the core components in SPARK.
- C++ Python Ada **SPARK**

Ericsson AB

August 2019 to January 2021 ##

Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Software developer • Implemented new features for the control plane of SGSN-MME in Erlang.

- Helped to migrate Ericsson's 5G platform from custom hardware to the telco cloud. Among other things, implemented a
- cloud-based storage and logging infrastructure for it. Linux Erlang Bash Python Kubernetes Docker

Chalmers University of Technology Doctoral researcher

Gothenburg, Sweden 9

September 2013 to September 2018 🛗

- Conducted research in the areas of automated theorem proving, formal methods and functional programming.
- Published and presented academic results in conferences and workshops (see my Google Scholar profile). Actively contributed to Vampire, a state-of-the-art automated theorem prover for first-order logic.
- Assisted to preparing assignments, conducting consultation sessions and grading exams in the courses on Functional Programming, Databases, Algorithms and Datastructures. · Developed and maintained a homework submission system in the Computer Science department used annually by
- approx. 1000 students and 20 faculty members. Oracle Database Java Haskell Python PostgreSQL

Amazon Web Services

Applied scientist intern, Automated Reasoning Group

New York, USA ?

March 2017 to June 2017 ##

Implemented an experimental backend for $\underline{\text{Tiros}}$ — a static analyzer of AWS virtual private cloud networks.

Scala Python Datalog Vampire Z3

Yandex Inc. Software developer

March 2011 to August 2013 mm Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

· Developed the back end of high-load web search services, including an in-house performant database solution

- capable of serving up to 400 requests per second. Developed information retrieval tools and web crawlers.
- Java Scala Akka Oracle Database MongoDB Redis

Developed an app recommendation system for Yandex.Store.

Motorola Solutions Inc.

July 2010 to December 2010 the Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

2005 to 2010 mm

Software engineering intern Designed a specification language for low-level telecom protocols and implemented a toolchain for it.

HTML

Python Wireshark Lisp

Freelance

JavaScript

Remote ♀ Web developer Developed front end and back end of commercial websites.

jQuery

Chalmers University of Technology, Department of Computer Science

CSS

Doctor of philosophy (Ph.D.)

Education

MySQL

PHP

Thesis titled "Automated Theorem Proving with Extensions of First-Order Logic"

September 2013 to September 2018 🛗

Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Ph.D. supervisors Laura Kovács and Andrei Voronkov Explored ways to make automated theorem provers more efficient for applications by extending the logic that they reason

Automated theorem proving Formal methods First-order logic Static analysis Vampire

Algebraic data types

Master of science (M.Sc.) September 2011 to July 2013 ## Saint-Petersburg State University, Department of Applied Mathematics Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

in. The applications include automation of proof assistants and static analysis of software and networks.

Scala Metaprogramming Monads Computational effects

Thesis titled "Syntactical Extensions of Scala for Effectful Computations"

Bachelor of science (B.Sc.)

Saint-Petersburg State University, Department of Applied Mathematics

September 2007 to July 2011 ##

Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

My GitHub profile

Docker

Thesis titled "Source Code Generation Based on Language Grammar Description"

Context-free grammars

Public software projects

vampire voogie Haskell An award-winning automated theorem prover A verification conditions generator for the Boogie

> intermediate verification language. atomizer Erlang

Scheme

An extension to Scala for boilerplate-free syntax for effectful A static analysis tool for finding loose atoms in large Erlang code bases.

fire HTML atp Haskell Python CoffeeScript

computations.

Haskell interface to automated theorem provers.

scala-workflow

for first-order logic.

Source code generation

A submission system for homework assignments.